Guide to the Jennifer Stafford Papers WAG.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Jennifer Stafford Papers
1992-2000
WAG.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet in 1 record carton
Jennifer Stafford was an Elevator, Ride and Tramway Engineer for the State of California. This collection focuses on the role of women in the International Union of Elevator Constructors and their struggle for recognition within the union. It contains legal papers from Adrian v. Dover, the first case dealing with sexual harassment brought by a group of Elevator Workers, a letter written by Stafford to city supervisors expressing concern that no women were being hired by elevator contractors, a report by Jennifer Stafford to the Human Rights Commission stating that elevator contractors were not fulfilling their minority goals on city jobs, papers from the Equal Rights Advocates, union membership cards, contracts and photographs.
Stafford, Jennifer.
Scope and Contents note
This collection focuses on the role of women in the International Union of Elevator Constructors and their struggle for recognition within the union. It contains legal papers from Adrian v. Dover, the first case dealing with sexual harassment brought by a group of Elevator Workers, a letter written by Stafford to city supervisors expressing concern that no women were being hired by elevator contractors, a report by Jennifer Stafford to the Human Rights Commission stating that elevator contractors were not fulfilling their minority goals on city jobs, papers from the Equal Rights Advocates, union membership cards, contracts and photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Materials were likely donated by Jennifer Stafford in 2002. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2002.002, 2002.004 and NPA.2005.250.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Separated Materials
Two posters ("Tradeswomen Past and Present") were separated from this collection and added to the Tamiment/Wagner Poster and Broadside Collection (GRAPHICS 002). Tools were removed and placed with 2005 acccessioned artifacts and ephemera. These tools include: an elevator half pick tool, an elevator door string tool, 2 samples of 5/8ths 8x19 steel elevator rope and one damaged elevator rope.
Historical/Biographical Note
Jennifer Stafford was an Elevator, Ride and Tramway Engineer for the Division of Occupational Safety and Health of the State of California.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
International Union of Elevator Constructors.; United States. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission.; Agreements.; Building trades |x Employees |x Labor Unions |z United States.; California (State); Newsletters.; Photographs.; Reports.; Sex discrimination against women |z United States.; Women in the labor movement |z United States.; Women |x Employment |z United States.
- Apprentice, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Elevator Constructor, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Elevator Union Standard Agreement, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Elevator Women of Local 8 [Photograph], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, Feb 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Award, Sep 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Equal Rights Advocate, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Haas School of Business (University of California, Berkeley), May 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Human Rights Commission, Nov 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- [Letter to Supervisor Carole Migden], July 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- [Litigation Files]: Adrian v. Dover, Nov 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Local 8's Story, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Need to Know, Dec 1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- OTIS Elevator Identification Card, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photographs from the Trade, 1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Tools for Survival, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Tradeswomen, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)